[blade ringing]
[metallic thwack]
[sword slicing]
[roaring reverberating]
[roaring]
[wind blasting]
This is the closest to freedom
I have been in a millennia.
Yet three more chains
keep me imprisoned.
Don't fear,
the Forbidden Five hunt
the remaining blades
as we speak.
[roaring reverberating]
[Roby] Yeah,
put that by the window,
the backlight
will be Stang-Zoot-Cubed!
That's the back of the piece.
Turn it around, please.
Huh. No, you were right,
it looked better before.
[bot mumbling]
When I'm done
with this remodel,
this place
ain't gonna be a museum,
it's gonna be a you-see-um,
with the huge crowds
that are gonna
come through here!
What, no reaction?
Even Uncle Bleckt
used to at least give me a scowl
for my genius wordplay.
Hermes?
-Hermes?
-[screeching awake]
Hermes...
I need you
to take this note to Geo
in the Land of Lost Things.
Another sculpture order.
Tell him
we need more blue in here,
but not azul.
I'd say we're pretty full up
on azul.
As they say,
too much Azul, is not a-cool.
Hold a sec.
Hey!
Wait, wait, wait, hey.
That's gotta go
right by the front entrance
to this floor.
That statue of me
is going to be the most
photographed art in here,
so we have to place it
in prime selfie light.
[smashing open]
[stone crumbling]
Hey, you can't just storm in--
Wait...
you're one of
the Forbidden Five!
Ah!
[blasting]
[screeching]
[screaming]
[scream fading]
What have they done to you?
You think you can
sneak up on me, child?
H'yah!
[smashing]
Whatever you need
that blade for,
Wyldfyre and the other Ninja
will kick your butt
all over the Merged Lands
before you can use it.
[cackling wickedly]
A funny one, you are.
Let us see
how hilarious you find
my Elemental Power of...
Decay...
[screaming]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja
for what's right ♪♪
You said you were taking me
to my parents.
There's nothing up ahead.
I mean, literally nothing.
[snarling]
Once again
you are misjudging
the situation.
Oh, am I?
You see anything
but miles and miles of sand?
Was I not right
about Master Wu
causing the Merge?
Just take me to my parents.
Like you promised.
That's what I'm doing.
No, you're leading me
across an empty desert.
I risked my life saving you.
I believed--
Stop.
[gasping]
[♪♪♪]
[glint dinging]
How...
how did you know this was here?
I have many resources
hidden across the Merged Lands,
as a contingency.
Now perhaps
you will cease doubting me.
I...
I'm sorry.
Do you know how to pilot
such a vehicle?
Yeah, pretty much.
When I was a mech racer,
my best friend Sor--
Uh, a long time ago,
someone taught me how to drive
and pilot all kinds of vehicles.
Hmm...
Show me what you've learned.
Huh...
[inhaling thoughtfully]
Okay, power should be...
[alarm ringing]
[hits button, alarm shuts off]
[wiper squeaking]
[mariachi music playing]
Yeah, that's there,
so this is...
[drone engine powers up]
It has a drone?
I-I mean, I knew that.
Just confirming.
There it is.
Now to make it land...
[pushing button]
Got to make it land
on the jet...
Ah!
Fool!
Whew!
[engine powering up]
I was going to hit that next.
Buckle up!
[power surges and backfires]
Oh, right, uh...
disengage landing gear.
Uh, okay, now hold on to--
[yelping] Whoa!
[wailing]
Hey, look!
Maybe Ras travelled on this,
and Arin dragged him?
Oh, makes sense.
Ras looked pretty hurt
last time we saw him,
and it would explain
their strange tracks.
What do you think, Frak?
Love it. Super cool.
You love Arin
pulling Ras on a sled?
I'm sorry,
I was kind of preoccupied
wondering what that
terrifying-looking place is?
I have no idea.
Looks like the edge
of another realm that merged.
We don't have to go there,
do we?
It's probably full of puppets.
I just know it.
[sniffing]
[grumbling]
Yep, this sled
was definitely Ras's.
[sniffing]
[grumbling]
Two sets of prints.
If Ras was injured,
it looks like he got better.
Only two sets.
Which makes it more likely
they are alone.
No Forbidden Five.
Where could the Five
have gone then?
Who knows, who cares?
We're back on track
to find Arin,
and that's
all that matters, right?
Let's go.
[grumble barking]
What is it, Riyu?
[grumbling urgently]
He wants us to follow him.
Uh, that's
the opposite direction
that Arin was headed!
Maybe someone needs help.
Riyu's never led us wrong.
Well, he has led us
to more than one noodle house
in the past.
And was that wrong?
Really?
We're just...?
Um, okay, but for the record,
I think this is a mistake.
Noted.
Hey there, Rapton here.
Are you sick of the 9-5?
[munching]
Rapton is here to invite you
on the ride of a lifetime.
We have a great
healthcare plan,
and you'll be rich!
And famous!
No autographs, please.
[♪♪♪]
Join the Freebooters
today!
Hello, handsome.
Whoa!
[grumbling]
What?
Primary...
electronics disrupted...
secondary elements--
Shh... Zane.
Save your energy.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
What makes you think
you can just use our stuff?
We stole all that gear
fair and square, lady!
If it wasn't for
that Nindroid there,
you and your poorly-named
"Freebooters"
would all be smashed
against that cliff.
Told you it was an awful name.
The only reason
you and your hair-piece
are still alive
is because of Zane,
who needs a lot of help
to survive this.
So you are not only
going to let me use your gear,
you are going to help me find
the pieces I need
to save him.
Have I made myself clear?
[clearing throat]
Uh, Freebooters,
I, Rapton,
have decided
it's up to us to save Zane.
So when Pixal here,
who's assisting me,
asks for something,
let her have it.
Unless it's like
super valuable,
and then still ask--
ask me first.
Also, this is definitely
my real hair.
Get me more parts
like these, please.
We are not going to lose
each other again, Zane.
Whatever it takes.
I don't get it.
How did Jay play
this old game remotely?
Nothing on the motherboard
allows remote access.
Hmm...
Did you check the fatherboard?
I'm thinking
he cheated somehow.
Only way he could have
beaten my high score.
Check for cheat-ware.
[sighing]
If we could figure out
how he transmitted the signal,
we could trace it back
to Jay's location, and--
--and force him to admit
he cheated!
[groaning]
[gasping] Yes!
Ooh...
Somebody's getting another
"love scroll".
Am not.
[giggling] Shut up.
Okay, I totally am.
[guffawing]
[gasping]
No!
What? Is Roby
breaking up with you?
Let's go kick his little butt!
No, Roby's hurt!
The City of Temples
was attacked!
[gasping]
Welcome to Arin Airlines,
we've reached
cruising altitude, so--
Your commentary
is not necessary.
Hey, what's that?
I know that place.
Lloyd and I were there.
What are you doing?
It looks like they need help.
Stay focused
on the task at hand.
We can't just ignore this.
If you're distracted
by everything in your path,
you'll never find your parents.
That's why Lloyd
is so ineffectual,
and he has clearly
passed his bad habits on to you.
Time to prioritize
your needs.
Oh, wow!
Look what we've found.
It's nothing.
And over there, more nothing!
When you get to know
Riyu better,
you'll learn to trust him.
If we'd stayed focused
on finding Arin,
we might already have--
[shrieking growl]
Riyu, what gives?
[grumbling]
I'm... not hearing anything.
Fan out!
The blade must be nearby!
We should have found it by now!
[quietly] Now we know
where the Forbidden Five are.
Well, one of them.
That's Tyr.
The leader
of the Dragonians we met.
The ones that helped us
out of the river?
What have the Forbidden Five
done to them?
Is this what
you wanted to show us?
[grumbling softly]
[Lloyd] They look corrupted,
maybe ancient magic.
The Five must've come through
the village after we did.
Those poor Dragonians...
[grumbling softly]
[Tyr growling]
You fools.
It's a small blade,
about this big,
of a shimmering metal.
ThunderFang said
you'd be able to sense it.
What's wrong with you?
He mean this?
[snarling]
[gasping]
Ninja?
[growling]
Give that blade to me!
Yeah, I'd say
this is what he's looking for!
Ninja... go!
Oh, dear.
I do hope I'm following
these operating instructions
from Master Zane correctly.
"Just walk up to the portal
and state
your desired destination."
Take me to Roby!
No, state your destination.
Take me to Roby town!
[together]
The City of Temples!
Let's go!
Thanks, Mr. Frohicky.
Hey!
When did that happen?
That portal
wasn't active before.
Who cares?
My boyfriend's
way more important
than stupid gates!
[door smashing]
Roby, what happened to you?
[sighing] Wyldfyre...
I knew you'd come.
[weakly] Rawr.
[gently] Rawr.
Whoever did this to you,
I'll heat blast them!
Then resurrect them again,
then heat blast 'em again!
It was
one of the Forbidden Five.
She got Hermes, too.
[croaking weakly]
The zootless jerk and her goons
came for a weapon.
The Five don't have
enough weapons already?
I should know the importance
of the Prismatic blade she took,
but I don't.
I used to think old lore
was a just waste of time,
like the Source Dragons
being a myth,
but I was wrong.
[groaning weakly]
Let me help with that.
Ah, thanks.
My eyes are getting worse.
I can't read this,
but the answers
could be in here,
"The Sagas
of the Eternal Sources"
by King Urd Leatherwing.
It's a book of history
my family kept.
You have to find out
what they're doing.
You have to stop
the Forbidden Five.
[coughing]
Shh...
Roby.
The Forbidden Five
are going to be
the Forgotten Zero
when I'm done with them.
[coughing]
[roaring]
Come on!
You were so nice before.
Can't we all just be cool?
[snarling]
[rumbling]
Quake works better
against people who stay
on the grou--
[wailing]
Tyr, buddy,
you got any tech on you?
Anything at all?
Guess not.
Then let's give Spinjitzu
another try.
Did I do it?
[wailing]
I don't think I did it!
[grunting impact]
[snarling]
Whoa-ah!
Unh!
[stomping heavily]
Uh-oh.
I hate that sound.
[grunting]
[roaring]
H'yah!
Rah!
That belongs to me.
I don't know exactly
who it belongs to,
possibly a giant,
creepy desert puppet,
but I 100% know
it doesn't belong
to the Forbidden Five!
Everything we desire
belongs to us
by right of conquest!
H'yah!
See, told you!
Told me what?
That we shouldn't follow Riyu.
You noted it.
Riyu can hear other dragons.
I bet he could sense
the Dragonians were in trouble!
Still shouldn't have followed!
[deep roaring overhead]
It's Zanth!
Zane found us!
Zane looks... different.
Pixal!
Where were you?
How'd you find us?
Zane's been looking for you!
Yes, we found each other.
[grunting]
H'yah!
Somebody had a glow up.
We haven't met.
I am Pixal.
I don't care!
You should.
You are attacking my friend,
and that is something
I will not tolerate.
Ah!
Dragonians, pull back!
We can always find you, Ninja,
and when we return,
you will give us the blade
or die defending it!
The what?
The blade!
You will give us the blade!
Parade?
Why would we give you
a parade?
That's not what I said!
We'll never throw you a parade.
'Cause of how you're evil.
[growling] Bah!
He clearly said "blade"
not "parade".
I know.
Pixal!
Oh, you're back!
And Zane, you're... huge?
What happened?
We will explain everything--
--but first, you must know
the Five are gathering
special blades
for an unidentified
nefarious purpose.
Yeah, blades like this.
It looks different,
but it sounds the same
as the sword
from my fight with Zeatrix.
It is made of
the same kind of rare metal
that sword was.
But why would the Five
want them?
You let the Ninja
get the blade?
They already had it.
I couldn't--
Ah!
Fail me again
and the Forbidden Five
will be the Forbidden Four!
Kur,
tell me you didn't also fail!
I got the blade,
but I found it like this.
Hmm...
We can fix it.
All it will take
is a little wish magic.
But all the Djinn are gone.
No.
Not all of them.
You said they'd be here.
No tricks?
No lies?
This is real,
my parents are there?
No lies.
Mom?
Dad?
No...
[panting]
[thunder rumbling]
Mom! Dad!
No!
[crying]
Why didn't you tell me?
Would you have believed me
without seeing it for yourself?
No.
How did they die?
That is unclear.
Whatever happened,
it must've been
because of the Merge.
But I can fix it all.
"Fix it"?
They're dead!
There's nothing to fix anymore.
Not true.
Reverse the Merge,
and you can create
anything in its wake,
and I will reverse the Merge.
That's why I, alone,
can save them.
What exactly are you saying?
Your parents.
My people.
Help me undo the Merge,
and they will return,
restored to life
like nothing ever happened.
[♪♪♪]